iscanmyfood.com 2012-06-24

# Privacy iScanMyFood checking chemical additives in our foods

Thank you for visiting the iScanMyFood.com site. We are committed to the privacy of our visitors. We collect no personal information about you when you visit our Web site unless you choose to provide that information to us.

Here is how we handle information about your visit to our Web site.

Information collected and stored automatically:

"Cookies" are small bits of text that are either used for the duration of a session ("session cookies") or saved on a user's hard drive in order to identify that user, or information about that user, the next time the user logs on the a Web site ("persistent cookies"). This Web site does not use persistent cookies or any other persistent tracking technology.

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the Web site, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store information like the following concerning your visit:

• The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com";

• Your IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our Web site;

• The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;

• The date and time you access our site;

• The pages you visit; and If you linked to our Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site, and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits.

Information protection:

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this hosting computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. If such monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, such evidence may be provided to appropriate law enforcement officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this server are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act or other law.

Information that you voluntarily provide:

We do not collect personally identifiable information unless you choose to provide it to us. If you provide us with personally identifiable information, for example, by sending an e-mail or by filling out a form and submitting it through our Web site, we use that information to respond to your message and to help us provide you with the information and services that you request. All uses of that information are described on the Web page containing the form.

Submitting voluntary information constitutes your consent to the use of the information for the stated purpose. When you click the "Submit" button on any of the Web forms found on our sites, you are indicating your voluntary consent to use of the information you submit for the purpose stated.

How information is used:

The information we collect is used for a variety of purposes (e.g., to register you for a conference, to respond to requests for information, and to fill orders). We make every effort to disclose clearly how information is used at the point where it is collected so you can determine whether you wish to provide the information.

Retention of Information:

We destroy the information we collect when the purpose for which it was provided has been fulfilled unless we are required to keep it longer by statute or official policy. Electronically submitted information is maintained and destroyed according to the principles of the Federal Records Act and the regulations and records schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration, and in some cases information submitted to us may become an agency record and therefore might be subject to a Freedom of Information Act request.

Also, iScanMyFood.com is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other sites that may link to the iScanMyFood.com web site.

Interaction with children:

This Web site offers some educational content to children under 13. No personally identifiable information is collected from these visitors unless voluntarily submitted as a request for information or services. The information supplied is used to respond to the user's inquiries or to provide services requested by the user.

Links to other sites:

Our Web site contains links to various other federal agencies and private organizations. Once you link to another site, you are then subject to the privacy policies of the new site. It is always a good idea to read the Privacy Policy of any site you visit.
